

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

11200 Greenwood Ave N., 34, Seattle, WA 98133

□ (206) 954-1418 | ■ erstaples@gmail.com | □ erstaples | ■ erstaples | □ erstaples

Summary _

Current software engineer on the Cloud Engineering team at NetApp. 7 years experience in the Kubernetes ecosystem, delivering value in cloud-native engineering, infrastructure automation, and site reliability roles. Strong track record of producing highly available services in distributed environments. Driven by curiousity and strong coffee.

Skills_____

Technologies Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, Ansible, Prometheus, Grafana, EFK stack

Languages Go, PHP, Bash, Python, JavaScript

OSS Contributions Cluster API, Cluster API Provider AWS, Helm Charts

Professional Experience _____

NetApp Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2019 - Present

- Developed alpha release that adds Azure support to cloud-native cloud volumes solution, turning it into a multi-cloud service.
- $\bullet \quad \text{Created the cluster provision system that is the backbone of "NKS" (NetApp Kubernetes Service), a production-grade managed Kubernetes service.}\\$
- Built Ansible playbooks and provided documentation for the support team to provide services to NKS customers more efficiently.
- Collaborated with front-end team to design and develop an API for the build system using gRPC.
- Contributed to Cluster API Kubernetes SIG via code contributions, Zoom office hours, and more.

Drud Seattle, WA

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER

Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Operated and iterated on "DDEV Live", a Kubernetes-based web-hosting platform and deployment pipeline for hundreds of CMS websites.
- Established and executed plan to deliver 99.99% uptime guarantee by implementing self-healing HA platform with resource-based autoscaling.
- Instrumented, configured, and tuned observability and monitoring stack using Prometheus metrics and alert dashboard, Fluentd, and LogDNA, with VictorOps and Slack integrations, which provided the foundation for new on-call rotations.

MedBridge Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / DEVOPS ENGINEER

Jan. 2015 - Jul. 2018

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2014

- Led effort to move deployment platform from Puppet to Kubernetes, which included translating Puppet manifests into Dockerfiles and Kubernetes specs and adopting technologies such as KOPS, Helm, Minikube, ELK stack, Kubectl, and Calico network policies.
- · Developed a set of Go and Bash tools to automate deployments and bootstrap dev machines with a local Minikube cluster.
- Reviewed and updated MedBridge services to ensure they met cloud-native best practices.
- · Designed active-active failover system to ensure MedBridge services met and exceeded SLA requirements.
- · Implemented cluster monitoring, logging, and alerting system using several open source projects.
- · Onboarded and remained an ongoing resource for the dev team for Kubernetes workflow via documentation, demos, and training sessions.
- Containerized / Dockerized PHP, Go, and Node applications and wrote manifest files to bring them to life in a Kubernetes cluster.

HCSS Sugar Land, TX

• Built tools in C#/.NET to manage and sync data between Azure and on-prem servers.

• Wrote custom reports in SQL based on customer needs.

R.R. Donnelley Houston, TX

Web Programmer

Dec. 2012 - Mar. 2014

• Developed UIs in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for web-to-print, variable-data print products.

Education __

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

University of Washington Seattle, WA

BA IN ENGLISH LITERATURE 2011

JANUARY 28, 2021 ERIC R. STAPLES · RÉSUMÉ